Register of the Eric Hoffer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, 1950-1985
  - Prints
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Janet Oberlund and Ruth and Reed Swenson, 1979 April (Box-folder 148: 16)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer and Lili Fabilli Osborne, two prints depicting Eric Hoffer individually, and two prints depicting Lili Fabilli Osborne individually, circa 1980 (Box-folder 148: 17)
    - Two prints depicting the dedication ceremony for a sculpture honoring Eric Hoffer, 1985 (Box-folder 148: 18)
  - Albums
    - One album of prints relating to visits by Eric Hoffer and Lili Osborne with E. C. and Mary Louise Rowand, Dallas, Texas, and San Francisco, California, 1970 (Box-folder 149: 1)
    - Two albums of prints depicting Eric Hoffer at Stonehill College, North Easton, Massachusetts, 1971 May (Box-folder 149: 2)
    - One album of prints depicting Eric Hoffer at Michigan Technological University, Houghton, Michigan, 1971 June 12 (Box-folder 149: 3)
    - Two albums of prints depicting Eric Hoffer during a visit to Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1977 (Box-folder 150: 1-2)
      Photographs taken by Dan Stroud
  - Oversize prints of photographs taken by George Knight
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer with Lee Greenwood, Sara Knight, and Selden Osborne, 1964 (Box-folder 151: 1)
    - One print depicting Lili Fabilli Osborne, 1966 (Box-folder 151: 2)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer at the University of California at Berkeley, 1966 (Box-folder 151: 3)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer working on the San Francisco waterfront, 1967 (Box-folder 151: 4)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer and Eric Osborne, 1964 (Box-folder 151: 5)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer and Sara Knight, 1967 (Box-folder 151: 6)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer and William Eaton, 1967 (Box-folder 151: 7)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer and Stephen Osborne, 1967 (Box-folder 151: 8)
    - One print depicting Lili Fabilli Osborne, Stephen Osborne, and Eric Osborne, 1967 (Box-folder 151: 9)
    - Two prints depicting Stephen and Eric Osborne, 1967 (Box-folder 151: 10-11)
    - One print depicting Stephen Osborne, 1968 (Box-folder 151: 12)
    - One print depicting a vase of flowers, 1968 (Box-folder 151: 13)
    - Two copies of a print depicting Eric Hoffer reading a newspaper, 1971 (Box-folder 151: 14-15)
    - One framed print depicting Eric Hoffer, 1971 (Box-folder 151: 16)
  - Oversize prints of photographs taken by others
    - Seven prints depicting Eric Hoffer with Lyndon Johnson at the White House, Washington, D.C., 1967 (Box-folder 151: 17-23)
      Two prints are signed, with a dedication to Hoffer, by Lyndon Johnson
    - Eight prints depicting Eric Hoffer in his study, 1970s (Box-folder 151: 24-31)
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer at a fundraising dinner for Israel, 1975 May (Box-folder 151: 32)
      Photograph taken by Bill Paul
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer, 1973 (Box-folder 151: 33)
      Photograph taken by Mimi Jacobs
    - One print depicting Eric Hoffer in Bartlesville, Oklahoma, 1977 (Box-folder 151: 34)
    - Two prints depicting the Earth as seen from Apollo 8 in lunar orbit, 1968 (Box-folder 151: 35-36)
    - One print depicting children playing, undated (Box-folder 151: 37)
- Motion Picture Film, undated
  - Passionate State of Mind, 16mm film (Box 152)
    One reel containing a CBS television interview with Eric Hoffer.
- Oversize Material, 1959-1985
  Albums, art works, awards, certificates, posters, and other oversize materials arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Albums
    - One album of correspondence between Eric Hoffer and Barney Brown, including some correspondence with persons other than Eric Hoffer and clippings, compiled by Barney Brown, 1971-1985 (Box-folder 153: 1)
      See also: CORRESPONDENCE/Brown, Barney
    - One album of photographs and clippings relating to the awarding of an honorary degree to Eric Hoffer, Muhlenberg College, Allentown, Pennsylvania, 1975 June 5 (Box-folder 153: 2)
  - Art works
    - Four drawings by Eric Osborne, undated (Box-folder 154: 1-4)
    - Seven etchings by Alec Stern, 1959 (Box-folder 154: 5-11)
    - Two brochures containing etchings by Alec Stern, 1959 (Box-folder 154: 12-13)
    - Four drawings by Bonnie N. Cooke illustrating aphorisms by Eric Hoffer, 1971 (Box-folder 154: 14-17)
    - One acrylic portrait of Eric Hoffer, 1966 (Art racks)
  - Awards, certificates, and honors received by Eric Hoffer
    - Commemorative paperweight, Geotechnical Society, University of California at Berkeley, undated (Box-folder 155: 1)
    - Commemorative paperweight, The Press Club of San Francisco, undated (Box-folder 155: 2)
    - Medallion awarded by the Commonwealth Club of San Francisco for The True Believer, undated (Box-folder 155 :3)
    - Framed certificate of appointment to the Art Commission of San Francisco, 1968 March (Box-folder 156: 1)
    - Plaque given in honor, Jewish National Fund, Los Angeles, California, 1969 August 29 (Box-folder 156: 2)
    - Framed certificate of membership, National Historical Society, 1970 March 1 (Box-folder 156: 3)
    - Certificate of honorary citizenship, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1970 June 28 (Box-folder 156: 4)
    - Certificate of appointment to the Art Commission of San Francisco, 1971 March (Box-folder 156: 5)
    - Metal plaque, with a facsimile of an honorary degree received from Michigan Technological University, 1971 June 12 (Box-folder 156: 6)
    - Metal plaque representing the Human Resources Award, Human Resources Congress, Chicago, Illinois, 1972 August 26 (Box-folder 156: 7)
    - Framed certificate of membership, Four Chaplains Legion of Honor, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1974 November 12 (Box-folder 157: 1)
    - Plaque given in appreciation, Hastings 1066 Foundation, Hastings College of Law, San Francisco, California, 1975 (Box-folder 157: 2)
    - Mounted certificate of honor, Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge, Pennsylvania, 1977 (Box-folder 157: 3)
    - Encased medallion for outstanding achievement, Freedoms Foundation at Valley Forge, Pennsylvania, 1978 (Box-folder 157: 4)
    - Encased Presidential Medal of Freedom, awarded, 1983 February 23 (Box-folder 158: 1)
    - Proclamation awarding Presidential Medal of Freedom, signed by Ronald Reagan, 1983 February 23 (Box-folder 158: 2)
    - Program for Presidential Medal of Freedom awards ceremony, 1983 February 23 (Box-folder 158: 3)
  - Brochure publicizing Eric Hoffer's newspaper column, "Reflections,", undated (Box-folder 159: 1)
  - Galley proofs of Truth Imagined, 1983 (Box-folder 159: 2)
    See also: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS for more materials relating to this title
  - Invitation in presentation album, "A Matter of Faith," Metromedia Producers Group, undated (Box-folder 159: 3)
  - Poem, "The Scholar," by W. Fred Wilson, in frame, undated (Box-folder 160: 1)
  - Posters
    - One poster advertising Eric Hoffer's newspaper column, "Reflections," in the Salt Lake Tribune, undated (Box-folder 160: 2)
    - Three printed copies of a poster advertising "People of Our Time," a Canadian Broadcasting Corporation series including a program devoted to Eric Hoffer, undated (Box-folder 160: 3)
- Memorabilia, undated
  - Four ceremonial sashes, worn by Eric Hoffer when receiving honorary degrees, undated (Box-folder 161: 1-4)
  - One Jewish prayer shawl (Box-folder 161: 5)
  - One embroidered Japanese silk brocade (Box-folder 161: 6)
  - Longshoreman's plug, with identifying serial number (Box-folder 162: 1)
  - Two cargo hooks used by Eric Hoffer in his work as a longshoreman (Box-folder 162: 2-3)
  - One wooden rack containing seven pairs of reading glasses and a magnifying glass (Box-folder 162: 4)
  - One leather bag (Box-folder 162: 5)
  - One wooden box given by Eric Hoffer to Lili Fabilli Osborne, containing two pipes, a packet of cigarettes, and a bag of pipe cleaners (Box-folder 162: 6)
  - One pair of cufflinks with the seal of the State of California, in a metal box (Box-folder 162: 7)
  - One cigarette case (Box-folder 162: 8)
  - One cigarette box (Box-folder 162: 9)
  - Two political buttons from the Zionist Organization of America (Box-folder 162: 10-11)
  - One nametag for the National Advisory Council (Box-folder 162: 12)
  - One cigar box containing three pocket knives, three coin purses, one eyeglass holder, and a tobacco pouch (Box-folder 162: 13)
  - One paperweight commemorating the American bicentennial, 1976 (Box-folder 162: 14)
- Not yet described (Box 163)